<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adeptus Dad</title>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <description>After a 20 years break, Adeptus Dad is revisiting Games Workshop Hobby with the kids.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 22:44:34 +0100</pubDate>
    
      <item>
        <title>Parametric Ork Missiles in OpenScad</title>
        <link>/2019/03/12/ork-missiles.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2019/03/12/ork-missiles.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/ork/missiles.png&quot; alt=&quot;missiles&quot; /&gt;
My &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/03/08/warhound-proteus-2.html&quot;&gt;recent order&lt;/a&gt; to Shapeways was the occasion to try something I whipped up a while ago: parametric ork missiles! For a long time, I’ve wanted to convert stantard shooty boyz to tankbustas simply by adding a missile to the front of their shoota. The reasoning being that firing a bullet in a missile was a very good way to launch it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was just needing some propa’ orky missiles, so I went to OpenScad. And of course, the beauty of OpenScad is that your 3D models can be &lt;em&gt;parametric&lt;/em&gt;. So, if you have a parametric missile model and some random values, you can generate any number of different missiles. The parameters I choose were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;radius of the missile&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;length of the warhead&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;length of the body&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;size of the fins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;number of fins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Main OpenScad code below. Feel free to reuse/modify it! I’ll post the result as I receive my order from Shapeways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/adeptus-dad/dfbb9b4c33fbc11f804af11db851f412.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Proteus Pattern Warhound: Alpha Design</title>
        <link>/2019/03/08/warhound-proteus-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2019/03/08/warhound-proteus-2.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With the positive reactions after yeasterday’s post on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/adeptustitanicus/comments/aye7z3/proteus_pattern_warhound_titan_in_openscad/&quot;&gt;r/adeptustitanicus&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/3Dprintedtabletops/&quot;&gt;r/3Dprintedtabletops&lt;/a&gt;, I was encouraged to finish the alpha design of the Proteus Pattern Warhound Titan’s replacement parts. The order is made on Shapeways, we’ll see in a few weeks if it all fits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see below a few beauty shots of the various parts. I think that I found a way to mount the plasma cannon sideways, I will leave the flamer for a later iteration (maybe with the Trident/Ursus Claw that I have had in mind for several weeks…)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/proteus/alpha1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/proteus/alpha1.png&quot; alt=&quot;alpha1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/proteus/alpha2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/proteus/alpha2.png&quot; alt=&quot;alpha2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/proteus/alpha3.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/proteus/alpha3.png&quot; alt=&quot;alpha3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/proteus/alpha4.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/proteus/alpha4.png&quot; alt=&quot;alpha4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/proteus/alpha5.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/proteus/alpha5.png&quot; alt=&quot;alpha5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The arms are designed to be magnetized. The shoulder sphere can receive a ∅3mm x 4mm magnet, and I plan to put a simple piece of metal inside the body. I hope that this way I can avoid polarity mistakes with the magnets and allow for easier posability of the arms (two magnets tend to align their axes, while I want a ball joint).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Proteus Pattern Warhound Titan in OpenScad</title>
        <link>/2019/03/07/warhound-proteus-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2019/03/07/warhound-proteus-1.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard they call the “new” Warhound design &lt;em&gt;Mars Pattern&lt;/em&gt;. So to keep in line with what GW has been doing with the Land Speeder, Land Raider, Missile Launcher, etc. let’s call the old (superior) design &lt;em&gt;Proteus Pattern&lt;/em&gt;. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/proteus/IMG_0333.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Desk&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I have these sitting on my desk and I must admit that I really don’t like this Mars Pattern body, it’s not very elegant (don’t start me on the Lucius Patterns!) So, the obvious solution is to whip out OpenScad and start modelling replacement bodies for my new plastic warhounds!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few hours, things are beginning to take shape…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/proteus/full.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenScad&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/proteus/partial.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenScad&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still a lot of adjustments to do: rivets (lots), various details, exhaust vents, etc. The arm is intended to mount the laser blasters and vulcan mega bolters sideways, to keep the old approach. I don’t think that the plasma and flamer weapons would work visually sideways. Different mounting arms will be needed. The whole thing is designed so that the weapons can be magnetized, and hopefully, the weapon cabling will get under the carapace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a work in progress, hopefully I will get the final design soon, and then… off to Shapeways!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ursus Claw 28mm</title>
        <link>/2019/01/08/ursus-claws.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2019/01/08/ursus-claws.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time in 1991, the original Adeptus Titanicus game was all the rage, and new weapons’ rules were published in White Dwarf 133. Among these new weapons, was the &lt;em&gt;Trident&lt;/em&gt;. This was a specialized very heavy weapon, and therefore reserved to Warlord-class titans (I don’t think Reavers could take this).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/ursus/trident.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WD133&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2012, Aaron Dembski-Bowden wrote a fine book named &lt;em&gt;Betrayer&lt;/em&gt; (the 24th novel in the Horus Heresy Series) featuring the Warhound-only Legio Audax (Ember Wolves) which intensively used a very similar weapon design. These &lt;em&gt;Ursus Claws&lt;/em&gt; allow the light titans to take literally down larger ones by using pack tactics and toppling big guys. The same kind of weapin were used on imperial navy ships for boarding assaults.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, some talented people started building them for the ForgeWorld resin titans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poom made himself an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tapatalk.com/groups/the_ammobunker/i-am-the-eightfold-path-t10581-s220.html?sid=14b3c2534997e2b844c2a996446f6cd2#p363694&quot;&gt;Ursus Claw&lt;/a&gt; for his chaos warhound titan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/ursus/top.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Top view&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/ursus/bottom.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Bottom view&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, on the blog of the excellent &lt;a href=&quot;https://aarondembskibowden.wordpress.com/2013/10/28/deathwatch-talon-and-the-rise-of-the-weekender/&quot;&gt;Aaron Dembski-Bowden&lt;/a&gt;, I found Benjamin Sephton-Smith’s Warhound with an ursus claw armament on his Morning Star Warhound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/ursus/morning_star.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Warhound&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More recently, the concept was transferred to knight, with the thundercoil harpoon available to Knight Valiants.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ignition!</title>
        <link>/2018/11/15/start.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2018/11/15/start.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello dusty old box!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3D Roleplay! Hobby Game!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
